A Guide to the Papers of Jerome S. Handler Relating to the African Burial Ground Committee 1991-1998
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- The African Burial Ground: Memorial Design and Fabrication: A Project In Cultural Storytelling Through The Environment-- Application/Competition/Contract for the Interpretative Center Site 1997 Dec 29 (Box 1)
- African Burial Ground Project: Classroom Study Guide and Glossary, Third Edition 1998, 2 copies (Box 1)
- Amendment of Solicitation/Modifications of Contracts 1997 (Box 1)
- Archeological and Anthropological Issues 1992-1994 (Box 1)
- Blueprints: "Perpetual Non-Exclusive Easement As Recited in Condemnation Documents of The Federal Government Dated October 13, 1990" and "African Burial Ground Interim Fence and Grading Plan" 1993 and 1995, 2 items (Box 1)
- Foley Square Project Federal Courthouse and Federal Office Building New York, New York (Draft): Research Design For Archeological, Historical, and Bioanthropological Investigations of The African Burial Ground and Five Points Area, New York, New York, General Services Administration Region 2--Prepared by Howard University and John Milner Associates 1992 Oct 15 (Box 1)
  bears JSH annotations and notes
- Foley Square Project Federal Courthouse and Federal Office Building New York, New York: Comments on The Draft Research For Archeological, Historical, and Bioanthropological Investigations of The African Burial Ground and Five Points Area, New York, New York, General Services Administration Region 2 1993 Jan. (Box 1)
  with JSH notes "GSA: comments Res. Design 2/20/93"
- Foley Square Project Federal Courthouse and Federal Office Building New York, New York: Research Design For Archeological, Historical, and Bioanthropological Investigations of The African Burial Ground (Broadway Block), New York, New York, General Services Administration Region 2 1993 Apr. 23 (Box 2)
  with JSH notes "Preliminary Reactions to Draft of Research Design 11/1/92": prepared by Howard University and John Milner Associates
- Ground Truth: published by Concerned Citizens for the Preservation of African-American Heritage 1992, 2 items (Box 2)
- Memorialization Artwork and Design Competition brochures 1998, 4 items (Box 2)
- Memorialization of The African Burial Ground/Federal Steering Committee: Recommendations Report to the U. S. Congress 1993 Aug. 6, 37 pp. (Box 2)
- Memorialization of The African Burial Ground/Federal Steering Committee: Recommendations Report to the U. S. Congress 1993 Aug. 6, 35 pp. (Box 2)
- Memorialization of The African Burial Ground/Federal Steering Committee: Recommendations Report to the U. S. Congress (blue draft) 1993 Aug. 6, 37 pp. (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous 1992-1998, 20 items (Box 2)
- Mueser Rutledge Consulting Engineers: Foundation Investigation, African Burial Ground site 1997, 3 items (Box 2)
- The New Ring Shout Public Art Project: Design Proposal 1994 Jan. 19, 3 items (Box 2)
- Newspaper clippings 1991-1993, 80 items (Box 2)
- Office of Public Education and Interpretation of the African Burial Ground (OPEI) 1993-1998, 30 items (Box 3)
- Slides and Photographs (a blue three-ring notebook) 1991-1994 (Box 3)
- Southern Illinois University at Carbondale: JSH letters and related 1992-1998, 13 items (Box 3)
- Steering Committee Agendas with correspondence and related materials 1992, 7 items (Box 3)
- Steering Committee Agendas with correspondence and related materials 1993, 29 items (Box 3)
- Steering Committee Agendas with correspondence and related materials 1994, 24 items (Box 3)
- Steering Committee Charter and General Services Administration Guidelines 1993 Sep.23, 2 items (Box 3)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1992 Jul. 26 (Box 3)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1993 Nov 15 (Box 4)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1993 Nov. 29 (Box 4)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1993 Dec. 20 (Box 4)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1994 Mar. 28 (Box 4)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1994 Apr. 25 (Box 4)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1994 May 23 (Box 4)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1994 Jun. 27 (Box 4)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes) 1994 Jul. 25 (Box 4)
- Steering Committee on The African Burial Ground of The City of New York (Minutes): Final Meeting 1994 Aug. 22 (Box 4)
- Testimony before the Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Grounds, House Committee on Public Works and Transportation, U. S. House of Representatives 1992 Sep. 24, 5 items (Box 5)
- Update: Newsletter of the African Burial Ground and Five Points Archaeological Project 1993-1998, 21 items (Box 5)